A Guide to the Papers of Rear Admiral Walter C. Ansel, 1924-1974
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
- American Published Articles
  - "The French Threat to British Shores, 1793-1798," by Donald R. Come. Miltitary Affairs (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 11)
  - "German Supreme Command in World War II," by Friedrich Ruge (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 12)
  - "The Glory that was Crete," by Robert Payne. New York Times Magazine, May 27, 1967 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 13)
  - "The Growth of Bureaucracy in Brazil, 1808-1821," by Alan Manchester (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 14)
  - "Hitler and Dunkirk," by Capt. Robert Asprey (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 15)
  - "Hitler: A Portrait in Retrospect," by Teleford Taylor. New York Times Magazine, Apr. 29, 1959 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 16)
  - "Hitler's Gamble," by H. Trevor Roper, Atlantic, Sept. 1954 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 17)
  - "How We Took Crete," by First Lieutenant Ernst Klienlein (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 18)
  - "The Human Factor in Deterrence," by Joesph I. Coffee U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings, Dec. 1964 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 19)
  - "Independence, Honor, and Ectasy in Crete," by Charles Haldeman. Vogue, Jan. 15, 1965 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 20)
  - "The Inside Story of Rudolf Hess," by Sir Ivone Kirkpatrick. Atlantic Monthly (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 21)
  - "The Last Days of the Grand Old Patient," by Lord Moran (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 22)
  - "Marine Combat Training Runs Temperature and Terrain Gamut," by T.W. Turner. Navy Magazine, Oct. 1964 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 23)
  - "The Mind of Adolf Hitler," by Walter C. Langer. New York Times Book Review, Dec. 1972 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 24)
  - "Montgomery and Conflicting Philosophies of Sea Power," by Col. J.D. Hittle, U.S.M.C. U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings, May, 1955 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 25)
  - "Naval Gunfire in Support of Landings," by Lt. Walter C. Ansel, U.S.N. U.S. Naval Proceedings, Jul. 1932 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 26)
  - "Naval Gunfire Today and Tommorrow," by Lt. Col. James B. Sooper, U.S.M.C. U.S. Naval Institiute Proceedings, Sept. 1966 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 27)
  - "The New Fleet Marine Force," by Robert B. Asprey U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings, Aug. 1959 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 30)
  - "Norway" (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 31)
  - "Operation Walkuere," by Lt. Verner R. Carlson, U.S.N. U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings, Jun. 1960 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 32)
  - "Point of No Return," by Donald MacIntyre. U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings, Feb. 1964 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 33)
  - "Professional Notes," by Capt. Alan M. Nibbs, U.S.N. U.S. Naval Proceedings, Nov. 1958 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 34)
  - "The Professional Officer and Foreign Policy," by Charles O' Leahy, Jr. U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings, Jul. 1964 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 35)
  - "Professor Herman and the Pendulum," by General Joesf Schmid (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 36)
  - "Russians in Iowa" (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 37)
  - "Salvo-Splash! The Development of Naval Gunfire Support in World War II," by Col. Donald M. Weller, U.S.M.C., Aug. 1954 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 38)
  - "A Sixty-Knot Landing Force," by Capt. M.J. Hanley, U.S.N. U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings, Mar. 1967 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 39)
  - "Some Old Snaphsots of the Master Race," by Sander Vanocur. The Reporter, Jun. 27, 1967 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 40)
  - "Some Personal Recollections of Adolf Hitler," by Capt. Heinz Assman U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings, Dec. 1953 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 41)
  - "Sword of Silk U.S.," by Capt. Boyd T. Bashare. Infantry School Quarterly, Oct. 1956 and Jan. 1957 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 42)
  - "The Transfer of the Portuguese Goverment to Rio De Janeiro," by Allan K. Manchester (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 43)
  - "The Twenty-Knot L.S.T.," by Commander J.H. Demythenare, U.S.N. U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings, Aug. 1966 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 44)
  - "U.S.S. Raleigh" (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 45)
  - "Why Hitler Did Not Invade England," New York Times Magazine, Jan. 6, 1965 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 46)
- German Published Articles
  - "Bericht uber das in Jahre 1940 seplant gewesene Englandinternehinen," by General Rausch, July 1945 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 1)
  - "Des Deutsche Besetzung von Danemark und Norwegen," by Alfred Schulze-Hinrichs, 1953 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 2)
  - "Eighteen May 1940" (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 3)
  - "Elite auf Eis Gelegt," by General Kurt Student (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 4)
  - "Der Entwurf zur Fuehrer - Weisung Nr. 32 von Juni 1941," by Karl Klee (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Extracts from Adolf Hitler's Speeches before the Reichstag, 19 Jul. 1940 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 6)
  - "Flugwehr und-Technik Arme et Technique de l'air," by Dr. Theo Weber (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 7)
  - "Graf Alfred Schlieffen Briefe," by Eberhard Kessel, 1958 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Jeder Reichsdeutsche in Ausland voliverplichteter Diener des Volkes und des Fuehrer," by Gauleiter E. W. Bohle (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 9)
  - "Lage nach Abschluss de deutschen Landoffensiven am Rande," des Mittelmeeres (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 10)
  - "Der Luftkrieg in Ralmen der 'Seelowe planung'," by Admiral Assmann, 1954 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 11)
  - "Die Luftschlacht un England," by F. Friewald, 21 Feb. 1953 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 12)
  - "Die Luftschlacht Am England in historischen Sicht," by Dr. Theo Weber (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 13)
  - "Reichmarchal Hermann Goering," by Buppo Schmid (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 14)
  - "Seelowe" (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 15)
  - "Strenght Luftwaffe: Beginning of War," by Bauntbach (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 16)
  - "Die Schlacht der verpassten Gelegenheiten," by Stefan T. Fossony (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 17)
  - "Uber Untershmen Kreta," by Richtofen, 1960 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 18)
  - "Verdamnte See SI," by Cajus Bekker (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Volkischer Beobachter (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 20)
  - War Diary of Feldmarshal Boch (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 21)
  - War Diary of General Alfred Jodl (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 22)
  - "Wandungen der Seekriegfuekrieg," by Vizeadmiral Kurt Assmann (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 23)
  - "Wer hat Roramel wirklich geschlagen? Montgomery?" Sonntag, 25 Sept. 1960 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 24)
  - "Zeittafel" by Bookler (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 25)
- Notes on Ansel's Books
  - Hitler Confronts England
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 29)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 30)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 31)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 32)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 33)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 34)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 35)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 36)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 37)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 38)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 39)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 40)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 41)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 42)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 43)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 44)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 45)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 46)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 47)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 48)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 49)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 50)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 51)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 52)
    - Notes Regarding Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 53)
  - Hitler and the Middle Sea
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 24)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 25)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 26)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 27)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 28)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 29)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 30)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 31)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 32)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 33)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 34)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 35)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 36)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 37)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 38)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 39)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 40)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 41)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 42)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 43)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 44)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 45)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 46)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 47)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 48)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 49)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 50)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 51)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 52)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 53)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 54)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 55)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 23)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 24)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 25)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 26)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 27)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 28)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 29)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 30)
    - Notes regarding Operation Merkur (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 31)
    - Operation Sea Lion Transcript, 1951 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 32)
    - Rough Drafts on Hitler Confronts England (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 33)
    - Notes on Crete (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 34)
    - Notes on High Ranking Political and Military Officials in Germany (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 35)
    - 17th Infantry Division (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 36)
    - Questions for General Halder (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 37)
    - Questions for General Alfred Topp (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous Notes
    - Amphibious Operations (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 39)
    - Japan (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 40)
    - War at Sea, 1914-1918 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 41)
  - Book Transcript of Hitler and the Middle Sea, by Walter Ansel
    - Chapter 1 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 2 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 3 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 4 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 5 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 6 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 7 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 8 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 9 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 10 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 11 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 12 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 13 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 14 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 15 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 16 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 17 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Chapter 18 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Chapter 19 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 20 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Chapter 21 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 21)
    - Chapter 22 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 22)
    - Chapter 23 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 23)
    - Chapter 24 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Chapter 25 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 25)
    - Index (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous Material (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 27)
- Maps, Sketches, and Drawings
  - German Plans for Invading England (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 1)
  - German Plans for Invading England (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 2)
  - German Plans for Invading England (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 3)
  - German Plans for Invading England (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 4)
  - German Plans for Invading England (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 5)
  - German Plans for Invading England (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 6)
  - German Plans for Invading England (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 7)
  - German Plans for Invading England (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Mediterranean (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 9)
  - French Coast (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 10)
  - French Coast (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 11)
  - French Coast (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 12)
  - French Coast (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 13)
  - French Coast (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 14)
  - French Coast (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 15)
  - French Coast (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 16)
  - French Coast (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Gibraltar (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 22)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 23)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 24)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 25)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 26)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 27)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 28)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 29)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 30)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 31)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 32)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 33)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 34)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 35)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 36)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 37)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 38)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 39)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 40)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 41)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 42)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 43)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 44)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 45)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 46)
  - Greece (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 47)
  - Malta (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 48)
  - Map Notes (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 49)
  - Map Notes (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 50)
  - Map Notes (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 51)
  - Map Notes (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 52)
  - Map Notes (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 53)
  - Tokyo (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 54)
- Personal Papers
  - Operation Husky (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Operation Husky (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Operation Husky (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Operation Husky (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Operation Husky (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Operation Husky (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Operation Husky (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Operation Husky (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Operation Husky (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous military reports (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Receipts (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Receipts (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Receipts (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Forrestal Fellowship (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Description of Wartime Experiences (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous Reference Materials
  - List of Pictures-General Windisch, April 1953 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Raeder und Hitler (in German), 1953 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous poetry (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 3)
  - "The Estimate of the Situation. Plans and Orders." Marine Corps Schools, 1931 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Newspapers and Magazine Clippings (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Photos and Negatives "Para Drops" (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Restricted Naval Material on Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Negative Photocopies of German Documents (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 8)
  - "Navy-The Magazine of Sea Power," 1964 & 1970 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Top Secret Document-U.S. Navy Pacific Fleet, Cruiser Division Six, June 1945 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Aus Politik und Zeitgeschite "Der Verbrecheriste Befehl," July 1957 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Navy Department Report-Study of Operation in Crete, 1941 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Document Transfer papers, Requests for Documents (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Synopsis of the opera "Reinzi" by Wagner (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Map Signals (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 15)
  - "Wetterbericht fur die Zeit...," 1940 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 16)
  - "Fur die Fuhrung des Luft-und Seekrieges gegen England," 1940 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Naval Group West August 25, 1940 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Naval Group East, photocopies of messages (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Aktennotiz (Sp. Report) (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous letters (in German) (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Photos and German Documents (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 23)
  - "Note on Die Deutsche Besetzung von Danemark und Norwegen 1940" (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 24)
- Oversized Materials
  - Administrative Boundary Map of the U.S., British, French, and Soviet Occupation Zones in Germany, June 1948 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)
  - Greater Germany Adminstrative Divisions, July 1, 1944 (Oversize Oversize, Box 1)